## CHRISTOPHER COMBS



hey@chriscombs.me http://www.chriscombs.me

Chris Combs is currently a remote worker in Saint Petersburg, Florida. He enjoys hacking on projects during nights and weekends that create great user experiences with beautiful UI. His non-work interest range widely, from reading about new technology to volunteering his time to humanitiarian organizations.

### SKILLS

DEVELOPMENT

FRONTEND JAVASCRIPT HTML 5 CSS 3 UI/UX VUE.JS NODE.JS REACT BACKBONE.JS AMPERSAND.JS JQUERY SASS LESS BOOTSTRAP SEMANTIC UI

BACKEND JAVASCRIPT NODE.JS EXPRESS MONGO POSTGRESQL DEVELOPMENT OF A PROPERTY OF A **GRAPE GIT** 

# **EMPLOYMENT**

Technology Business Analyst, Humana

2014-11 — Present

Provided systems analysis and process integration for a Taleo Enterprise system for human resources. Also provided second-level support for issues arising with the Taleo platform.

 Researched all the capabilities of our system and provided insight as to why our system was lacking stability.

Taleo Performance Management Talent Management

Technology Applications Engineer, Humana

2012-12 - 2014-11

Designed, developed and implemented enterprise applications using Oracle Applications Express for home and skilled care nursing operations. Also provided second-level support for issues arising from the use of these enterprise applications.

- Redesigned an in-house care management suite using a modern web framework (Bootstrap), vanilla JavaScript and agile methodologies.
- Developed a better user experience to assist our customer service representatives on-board new members into our programs.
- Developed a system to maintain, notify and update nursing licensure. Replacing an Excel spreadsheet system for managing licensure for up to 5,000 nurses with licenses across 50 states.

**Oracle Applications Express** 

#### Pharmacy Reporting Analyst, Humana

2011-06 - 2012-12

Proactively identify, evaluate, and solve problems with rigorous logic, a systematic approach, and creative

• Developed and deployed a Microsoft Access front-end and a SQL Server back-end customer relationship manager. This tool had the ability to keep track of members, faxes, reporting, and even access pharmacy systems for a outbound member services department. This tool helped save pur department from hiring at least two extra employees.

MS Access SQL Server SQL Service Reporting Services SharePoint

#### Pharmacy Technician, Humana

2008-11 — 2011-06

Worked as a Pharmacy Technician in different aspects of the mail order pharmacy business. Ranging from Item Entry, Failed/Exception Claims and Member Services. All of these positions required that I maintain certification in being a Pharmacy Technician and continuing education.

Developed a tool that was able to screen scrape the antique pharmacy system and impose as a technician to quickly move orders, items and comment on profiles. This work didn't require a technician to review and it became an automated process there after.

Excel

## **PROJECTS**

Creator, Highway - A Local Responder Dispatching System

This project will help dispatch a local responder to disasters or anyone you want to an event. It can provide communication between the dispatcher and responder via SMS or Mobile app. Geographical boundaries can be plotted; along with on-call scheduling to make sure the correct person is being dispatched. Nodaljs Node js Vue is Twilio

#### Creator, Pinellas 911 - A Public 911 CAD

This project maps and displays in real-time fire/ems department calls. It can tell you what apparatuses are responding, enroute, onscene and if they've cleared the call. Also gives you markers of the current calls and nearest fire stations.

- Developed in Meteor.js, re-designed/developed in Vue.js
- Mobile first approach
- Progressive web app

Vue.js Node.js Mongo

### **EDUCATION**

*No Degree - Pre-medicine*, University of Cincinnati 2009-09 — 2012-06

*No Degree - Zoology*, Miami University of Ohio 2006-08 — 2008-07

**SERVICE** 

Disaster Action Team - Area Coordinator, American Red Cross 2015-06 — Present

General Volunteer, American Red Cross 2014-07 — Present

WRITING

Chris Combs, Medium.com 2015